List<Map<String, dynamic>> ECGPartFourQuestions = [
  {
    'question':
        'A patient presents with a heart rate of 40 bpm, a regular rhythm, and narrow QRS complexes. What is the likely diagnosis?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial fibrillation.',
      'Ventricular tachycardia.',
      'Sinus bradycardia.',
      'Supraventricular tachycardia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which segment of the ECG is often used to evaluate for myocardial ischemia or infarction?',
    'answers': ['P segment.', 'PR segment.', 'QRS segment.', 'ST segment.',],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which electrolyte imbalance is associated with a prolonged QT interval and an increased risk of arrhythmias, including torsades de pointes?',
    'answers': [
      'Hypernatremia.',
      'Hypokalemia.',
      'Hypercalcemia.',
      'Hypocalcemia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the primary purpose of the P wave on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial depolarization.',
      'Ventricular depolarization.',
      'Atrial repolarization.',
      'Ventricular repolarization.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which arrhythmia is characterized by a regular rhythm and a wide QRS complex, often seen in patients with bundle branch block?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial fibrillation.',
      'Atrial flutter.',
      'Ventricular tachycardia.',
      'Supraventricular tachycardia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the most common cause of ST-segment depression on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Myocardial infarction.',
      'Pericarditis.',
      'Bundle branch block.',
      'Atrial fibrillation.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which segment of the ECG represents ventricular depolarization?',
    'answers': ['P wave.', 'PR interval.', 'QRS complex.', 'ST segment.'],
    'correctIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the primary purpose of the QRS complex on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial depolarization.',
      'Ventricular depolarization.',
      'Atrial repolarization.',
      'Ventricular repolarization.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question': 'Which coronary artery supplies the lateral wall of the heart?',
    'answers': [
      'Left anterior descending (LAD).',
      'Left circumflex.',
      'Right coronary artery (RCA).',
      'Posterior descending artery (PDA).',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which lead on a 12-lead ECG is positioned at the fifth intercostal space at the midclavicular line on the left side?',
    'answers': ['Lead I.', 'Lead II.', 'Lead V1.', 'Lead V5.',],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which lead on a 12-lead ECG is often used to diagnose right ventricular hypertrophy?',
    'answers': ['Lead I.', 'Lead II.', 'Lead V1.', 'Lead V4R.',],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'In which lead is the R wave typically largest in the precordial leads (V1-V6)?',
    'answers': ['Lead V1.', 'Lead V2.', 'Lead V3.', 'Lead V4.',],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the primary purpose of the U wave on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial depolarization.',
      'Ventricular depolarization.',
      'Atrial repolarization.',
      'Late ventricular repolarization.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which electrolyte imbalance is associated with a prolonged PR interval and prominent U waves on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Hypernatremia.',
      'Hypokalemia.',
      'Hypercalcemia.',
      'Hypocalcemia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'A patient presents with ST-segment elevation in leads II, III, and aVF. Which coronary artery is likely occluded?',
    'answers': [
      'Left anterior descending (LAD).',
      'Left circumflex.',
      'Right coronary artery (RCA).',
      'Left main coronary artery.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which ECG lead is often used to diagnose left posterior fascicular block?',
    'answers': ['Lead I.', 'Lead II.', 'Lead III.', 'Lead aVF.',],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the most common cause of ST-segment depression in leads V4-V6 on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Myocardial infarction.',
      'Pericarditis.',
      'Bundle branch block.',
      'Right ventricular hypertrophy.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which segment of the ECG represents the time it takes for ventricular repolarization?',
    'answers': ['P segment.', 'PR segment.', 'QRS complex.', 'T wave.',],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which electrolyte imbalance can cause a prolonged QT interval and an increased risk of torsades de pointes?',
    'answers': [
      'Hypernatremia.',
      'Hypokalemia.',
      'Hypercalcemia.',
      'Hypocalcemia.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the primary purpose of the T wave on an ECG?',
    'answers': [
      'Atrial depolarization.',
      'Ventricular depolarization.',
      'Atrial repolarization.',
      'Ventricular repolarization.',
    ],
    'correctIndex': 3,
  },
];
